mydollbestfriend.co.uk 2019-01-13

# Privacy & Cookies Policy

**PRIVACY AND COOKIES POLICY**

Effective Date: 23rd May 2018

**1\. Who are we?**

1.1 We are My Doll Best Friend Ltd **** trading as “My Doll Best Friend”. **** For privacy queries, you can contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) Other contact details are on our website.

**2\. What’s the point of this policy?**

2.1 It tells you what to expect when we collect your personal information (which includes personal information about you but also information that can be used to track you such as your IP address - see further below). Please only use our site if you are completely happy with this policy.

2.2 Generally, the policy covers only information provided to us. If you give personal information to other people, such as payment providers or other websites, please check their privacy policies.

**3\. Might the policy change?**

3.1 Yes. **** Please check whenever you visit our website. We will assume you agree to the new version of the policy if you use the site after its effective date.

**4\. What personal information do we collect?**

4.1 Information which you upload to our site or otherwise give us (e.g. via our site or by phone or email or contact form) such as your name, contact details, how you heard about us as well as any personal information which you include in public activities on our site, e.g. reviews, uploaded photos, posts or comments. Please note that calls to our contact centre may be monitored or recorded.

4.2 Limited information made available to us by our payment provider for verification purposes e.g., your IP address used for payment, fraud score, email address, trading name and card address.

4.3 Automated information such as the internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your device to the internet, connection information such as browser type and version, information about your device including device-type and device identifier, operating system and platform, mobile network data, a unique reference number linked to the data you enter on our system, login details, the site from which you arrived at our site, details of your activity with date / time stamps including pages you visited and your searches / transactions. 

**5\. What's our reason/ legal basis for collecting the information?**

5.1 Because it’s necessary to provide you with our goods or services under our contract with you. We may use it for other purposes (such as email marketing) if you consent. In the case of other data such as automated information collected when you browse our site, we use this to manage and improve our site in accordance with our “legitimate interests”.

**6\. What about cookies?**

6.1 We and/or third parties use cookies and other tracking technologies on our website. A cookie is an identifier (a small file of letters and numbers) that is sent to your computer.  Our website’s functionality will be limited if you configure your browser to reject cookies.

6.2 Cookies are widely used to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the website owner or others. Session cookies are temporary cookies that remain in the cookie file of your browser only until your browser is closed. They allow websites to link your actions during a browser session. Persistent cookies stay in the cookie file of your browser for longer (how long will depend on the lifetime of the specific cookie). For further information on cookies, including how to use your browser to block them and how to delete cookies already stored on your device, visit: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

6.3 The following kinds of cookies may be used on this website:

a)  ** _Cookie testing:_** We use a number of session cookies to test whether your browser has cookies enabled.

b)  ** _Magento cookies:_** __ The following cookies relate to Magento, our shopping cart system: Session cookies keep track of your movement from page to page, authenticate you and store your selections so you do not get asked repeatedly for the same information.  For example, a session cookie remembers your shopping cart selection so you will have the items you selected when you are ready to check out. Persistent cookies (up to one year) remember your settings such as favourites, wishlist items, preferred currency and recently viewed products to result in an enhanced experience when you revisit our site. See [here](https://docs.magento.com/m2/ce/user_guide/stores/cookie-reference.html) for a list of cookies provided by Magento. These cookies are essential for our service.

c)  ** _Cloudflare cookie_** _:_ Cloudflare places a persistent cookie (up to 5 years) to identify trusted web traffic. Click [here](https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170156-What-does-the-CloudFlare-cfduid-cookie-do-) for more information and [here](https://www.cloudflare.com/cookie-policy/) to see Cloudflare’s cookies policy. This cookie is essential for the security features used by our service.

d)  ** _Google cookies_** _:_   Persistent cookies (up to four years we believe) are set in connection with the following Google services on our site and these cookies may involve certain information (such as your IP address and web address of the page you’re visiting) being sent to Google:

i)  ** _Google Analytics (“GA”)_** _:_ We use cookies to recognise and count the number of website visitors as well as providing other information about the visit such as duration, route through the website and what sites the visitor came from. This information helps us to improve the way our website works, for example by making sure users find what they need easily. You can specifically opt out of GA [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). See below for other opt out routes. 

**_More information and opt out:_** Click [here](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) for Google’s privacy policy and [here](https://www.google.co.uk/policies/technologies/types/) for more information about the kinds of cookies placed by Google. Click [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) for information about how Google uses data from its partners’ sites or apps as well as different ways to opt out of Google cookies. ****

e)  ** _Wordpress cookies:_** We use Wordpress persistent cookies (up to one year) to identify logged-in users, to remember you when you move from page to page so you don’t have to log-in again on each page, to customise your view of our interfaces and to avoid visitors who make repeat comments having to re-enter their details.  Click [here](https://codex.wordpress.org/WordPress_Cookies) for some technical information from Wordpress about these cookies. These cookies are essential for our site.

f)  ** _Buddypress cookies:_** Buddypress is a social media plugin for Wordpress. We use Buddypress session and persistent cookies (up to one year) to help you ensure that you are not presented with activity that you have already viewed on community pages, to help with page reloads and to remember your Buddypress settings.

g)  ** _Social media cookies:_** We may use various social media sharing and other features including: [Facebook](http://www.facebook.com/help/cookies), [Twitter](https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-cookies)), [Google Plus](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies), [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy), [Pinterest](https://policy.pinterest.com/en-gb/cookies), [Instagram](https://help.instagram.com/1896641480634370?ref=ig). [YouTube](https://policies.google.com/technologies/cookies).  These features may involve the relevant companies using cookies or linking your visit with cookies previously placed by them on your computer in order for them to collect information relating to your visit to our website or your interaction with their services or otherwise. Click the links shown above for further information including how to opt out where this is possible.

h)  ** _Facebook advertising cookies / “Facebook pixel”:_** Facebook places third party persistent cookies to enable the display of interest-based ads (i.e. relating to your visit to our site) when you’re on Facebook and to provide measurement services relating to your activity. Click [here](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/) for more information including how to opt out.

i)  ** _Cookie-warning cookie:_** This cookie takes note of whether you are happy to accept cookies on this website based on your response to the message which appeared when you first visited the website. This persistent cookie will remember your preference for up to 90 days.

**7\. What do we do with personal information?**

7.1 Provide our site, e.g. send service messages, process payments, fulfil orders.

7.2 Send you marketing messages, if you have given permission. You can withdraw permission at any time as explained on our site or by emailing us at the above email address.  

7.3 Use it to recognise you when you visit or return to our site to track anonymised traffic and usage patterns, prevent or detect fraud or abuses and help us improve our site.

**8\. How long do we keep it?**

8.1 We will generally keep your information for up to six years after your account is closed - for tax reasons and/or to help deal with any disputes. That timeframe may vary if we are legally required to keep information for a particular period. We will keep your information which we use for marketing until you tell us to stop sending you marketing messages.  We will remove public information about you on our site if you email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to request removal and/or to close your forum account.   

**9\. To whom do we send or make available your personal data?**

9.1 To other people who supply us with a service, e.g. **** couriers (to enable delivery of goods), warehouse storage and fulfilment providers, e-commerce platform providers, web developers, website hosts, accounting and form-building services, content delivery networks and businesses which help us send communications or monitor our website.

9.2 To Reviews.co.uk (name, email address, IP address and product purchased) to enable them to invite to you to review your purchase on their siteour site.

9.3 To other users of our site, if you enter personal information into a public profile or otherwise include it in a post, comment or other public action on our site. If you use our forum, your activity and membership status are visible to other users.

9.4 To the police or other relevant authorities or to complainants, if we think the personal information breaches our terms and conditions, or it is necessary to protect us or others, or that a criminal offence may have been committed, or where required by law or where requested by the police or other appropriate authorities.

9.5 To potential buyers so far as reasonably necessary, in the case of an actual or proposed (including negotiations for a) sale or merger or business combination involving all or the relevant part of our business.

**10\. What happens to your personal data?**

10.1 These go direct to our payment partners. We do not receive such information except as stated above.  To ensure your details are not being used without consent, our payment partners may send your personal information to relevant third parties including credit reference and fraud prevention agencies, who may keep a record of that information.

**11 Do we send your information outside the European Union?  **

11.1 Your personal information which we collect is stored within the EU and is not transferred to any third countries except for the following.

11.2 Your personal information may be transferred to the US by the following companies certified under the [EU-US Privacy Shield Framework](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_en), which provides certain safeguards for your personal information: Google (analytics), Mailchimp / Mandrill (email delivery), Mailgun (email delivery), Cloudflare (security), Amazon Web Services (web hosting), SurveyMonkey Inc / Wufoo (form building services), Facebook (advertising / analytics).

**12 What rights do you have?**

12.1 If the legal requirements are met: To ask us for access to your personal information, to rectify it if there are mistakes, to delete or restrict or object to its use in certain circumstances or to “data portability”.

12.2 If you have a complaint about how we are dealing with your personal information, please contact us via the email address above. If you are not happy with our response or think we are not handling your personal information in accordance with the law, you can complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).

12.3 For more information about your rights, visit the ICO’s website: [www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/).

Version: P&C.V.3. Effective Date: 23rd May 2018
